Lee Jackson Papers
Lee Jackson Papers
1915-1964
Jackson, Lee, 1909-
0.3 linear ft.
Papers of the American painter. Collection includes correspondence, exhibition catalogs, photographs of work, articles and clippings about Jackson.
149076
Biographical History
Lee Jackson (1909-2002) was an American painter known for his figure and animal paintings.
Born in New York City on February 2, 1909, he studied at the Art Students League in New York and with the artists William McNulty, George Luks and John Sloan. His work has been exhibited at the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, National Academy of Design, Golden Gate Exposition in San Francisco in 1939, Carnegie Institute, Whitney Museum of American Art, Art Institute of Chicago, Audubon Association, Boston Museum of Fine Arts and many other major museums. He also had one-man shows at several galleries in the United States and Canada.
Jackson was a member of the Art Students League, the Audubon Association, Artists Equity Association, and the American Watercolor Society. He won prizes from Grumbacher (1951) and the National Academy of Design (1951) and received a Guggenheim Fellowship in 1941.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Lee Jackson Papers consist of biographical material, correspondence, subject files and published material.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is subdivided into incoming, arranged chronologically, and one outgoing item. Subject files are arranged alphabetically. Published material is subdivided by type and arranged chronologically.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Painters; Jackson, Lee, 1909-; Art, American.; Art, American -- 20th century.; Painters -- United States.; Painting, American.; Painting, American -- 20th century.; Articles.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Exhibition catalogs.; Photographs.; Artists.; Painters.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Miscellaneous, undated; biographical sketch, list of Jackson's works (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming, 1940-1941; 1943,; 1945,; 1947-1951,; 1964 (Box 1)
  - Outgoing, 1948 (Box 1)
- Subject files
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1939; 1941,; 1943,; 1949,; 1951 (Box 1)
  - Invitation, undated (Box 1)
  - Photographs
    - Of Jackson, 1915; 1940,; 1949 (Box 1)
    - Of Jackson's work, 1935; 1938,; 1940-1941,; 1946-1947,; 1949 (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Magazine articles about, 1953; includes reproduction of work (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings about Jackson and his work, 1941; 1943,; 1945-1947,; 1949 (Box 1)